

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

Dallas-Fort Worth Area United States 847-322-9793 derinjoseph23@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Personal Site

Github

Skills

JavaScript

Java

Python

React

Springboot

SQL

Git

CSS

HTML

jQuery

JSON

Mentorship

Leadership

Hobbies

Basketball Go Kart racing Gaming

Profile

Experienced and self-motivated generalist engineer who specializes in building web applications. I started programming when I was 16 and I ended up making a career out of it. I am currently modernizing State Farm's auto insurance applications. I am always interested in learning new technologies and helping other people enter the field or progress in their careers.

Employment History

Software Engineer II, State Farm

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT

- Modernizing state farm's auto insurance application by replacing an older framework (SFX) with a newer framework (1X).
- Collaborating with an agile team of 7, and helped prioritize and scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Utilizing Spring Boot and Java for building services and business logic.
- Improving test coverage using TDD and utilizing GitLab for DevOps.

Software Engineering Mentor (Volunteer), CareerVillage

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

- CareerVillage is a community where students can get free personalized career advice from real-life professionals.
- Volunteering my time to help students that want to get into the field of software engineering.

Software Engineer, State Farm

AUGUST 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Developed a greenfield banking application with the latest web technologies like React, and Ember.
- Rewrote the SOAP back-end logic for our existing application using REST.
- Ensured 95% test coverage using JUnit 5 for all Java code written by the team.

Software Engineer (Volunteer), Keep Dallas Beautiful

JANUARY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Keep Dallas Beautiful's mission is to improve the quality of life in Dallas through community-driven projects that create a cleaner, greener city full of vitality.
- Helped create a prototype web application for the organization that lets users sign up for projects that help keep Dallas clean.

Education

M.S in Information Technology: Software Development and Management, Liberty University

• Coursework: Secure Software Engineering, Statistical Analysis & Data Mining, Database management, Software Development Management.

B.S in Information Technology: Web and Mobile Development, Liberty University

Coursework: Software development, Advanced Object-Oriented
Programming, Networking, Database management, Internet architecture.

Associate of Applied Science: Web Development and Design, Dallas College

 Coursework: Web Design Technology, Advance Program Concepts, Web Server Software, Web programming.